Finding aid to Smith Club of Sarasota records CA.MS.00136
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Sarasota records
1946-2006
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Sarasota
CA.MS.00136
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
The Smith Club of Sarasota records contain minutes, photographs, membership directories, financial records, and various materials documenting the club's history and activities.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Club of Sarasota, Florida, was started in 1947 by Mrs. Louise Whitaker, the first acting president of the club, and consisted of fifteen members. One of the club's major fundraising activities is the sale of pecans. The money raised goes towards the Smith College of Sarasota Scholarship Fund, which provides scholarship assistance to a Smith student from Florida. Additional club activities also included the sponsorship of the annual Book Awards, joint meetings with the Wellesley Club of Sarasota and a tradition of welcoming Smith alumnae and faculty from a variety of fields as speakers. In January of 1978 former Smith College president Jill Ker Conway was the guest of honor and speaker at a club luncheon. The club also published its own member newsletter.
Scope and Contents
The Smith College Club of Sarasota records consist of materials including club by-laws; correspondence and meeting notices; fundraising records; club newsletters; membership and officer information; annual, executive board and club meeting minutes; photographs; publicity; financial records; obituaries, and event notices.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith Club of Sarasota records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Related Materials
- 90. Alumnae Association
Smith College - Alumni and alumnae - History - Sources
- Annual Reports, 1976-2002 (Box 1)
- Bylaws, 1948-97 (Box 1)
- Articles of Incorporation, 1997 (Box 1)
- Officers, 1947-99 (Box 1)
- Membership Directories, 1974-81 (Box 1)
- Membership Directories, 1981-88 (Box 1)
- Membership Directories, 1988-95 (Box 1)
- Membership Directories, 1995-2002 (Box 1)
- Membership Lists, 1950s-80s (Box 1)
- Obituaries, 1954-2001 (Box 1)
- Nominating Committee, 1997-99 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence - First Meeting, Feb 13th; 1947 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1949-51 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1952-55 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1956-60 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1960-66 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1966-79 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1980-86 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1987-91 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1992-96 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1997-2003 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, March 24th, 1976 (Box 1)
- Annual Meeting, March 24th, 1976, Photographs (Box 1)
- In Brief - Meetings, 1963-81 (Box 1)
- Executive Board Minutes, 1992-2003 (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Book, 1947-69 (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1951-56 (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1956-69 (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1969-93 (Box 1)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1994-2002 (Box 1)
- Dues, 1965-2002 (Box 1)
- Scholarship Fundraising - Pecans, 1977-2003 (Box 1)
- Tax Exemptions, 1992-2002 (Box 1)
- Capital Campaign, 1967-70 (Box 1)
- 75th Anniversary Fund, 1950 (Box 1)
- 75th Anniversary Fund - Honey Project, 1947-50 (Box 1)
- Scholarships, 1952-99 (Box 1)
- Misc. Receipts and Records, 1980-96 (Box 1)
- Internships, 1997-2002 (Box 1)
- Smith Club Gifts, 1980-96 (Box 1)
- Meeting Notices, 1971-2006 (Box 1)
- Programs, 1975-2002 (Box 1)
- Events and Clippings, 1946-47 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1948-49 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1950 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1951 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1952 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1953 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1954 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1955 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1956 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1957 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1958-59 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1960-61 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1962-63 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1964-65 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1966-67 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1968-69 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1970-71 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1972-73 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1974 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1975 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1976 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1977 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1978 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1979 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1980 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1981 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1982-83 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1984-89 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1990-97 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1998 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 1999 (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, 2000- (Box 2)
- Events and Clippings, undated (Box 2)
- Smith College Newsletters and Magazines (Box 2)
- Lois Bennett Real Estate News, 1999-2002 (Box 2)
- Alumnae Council of 86 and Sophia Smith Bicentennial, 1986; 1996 (Box 2)
- Music Lectures, 1953-95 (Box 2)
- Frank Hopper - Correspondence and Artwork, 2001 (Box 2)
- Smith and Wellesley Clubs Join Meeting, 1979-97 (Box 2)
- President's Letters to Club, 1990-2001 (Box 2)
- 25th Anniversary Party, 1972 (Box 2)
- Newsletter, 2002-04 (Box 2)
- Guestbooks, 1951; 1974 (Box 2)
- Photographs (Box 2)
- Club Binder (disassembled) (Box 2)